hifipublic.com 2015-06-22

# Privacy & Terms | HiFi Public

## Welcome to HiFi Public

You’ll find a vibrant and growing community of smart, enthusiastic people at HiFi Public _.  _ Our goal is to foster conversations that are helpful, informative, and fun. We very much would like you to help us do just that, so here are some guidelines for how to participate.

### THE SHORT VERSION

  * We’re so glad you’re here! We hope you will help create great conversations in our community.
  * Don’t be a jerk, call people jerks, or react to jerks. We’ll remove bad stuff when we see it.
  * Respect and help the moderators. It’s a small team of dedicated, caring humans working hard to make things better.

### HOW TO REGISTER AND CUSTOMIZE YOUR PROFILE

You can register by clicking “Join” on the avatar in the menu and then you can either register directly or register with your Facebook, Google+, or Twitter. You may be interested in checking out our [Privacy Policy](http://hifipublic.com/hifi4/privacy-policy) and [Terms of Use](http://hifipublic.com/hifi4/terms-of-use) if yo care about the legal stuff.

The next step is to customize your profile. You can upload a photo and tell everybody a little about yourself. You can also edit your account settings to link your Facebook and Twitter accounts. You can always edit your profile by clicking your own avatar in the upper-left hand corner of the site.

### HOW TO POST AND COMMENT

There are three ways to interact on _  Hifi Public_. Here’s the basics, but there’s much more information down below.

  * **Post a comment:**  We love comments, and simply by registering you can comment on any story on  _HiFi Public_. Comments are organized into collapsable threads to make it easy to follow a conversation. There are also some really great keyboard shortcuts on comments — they’re listed on the right of the comments area. If you realize you’ve made a typo, you’ll have 90 seconds to edit your comment before it’s set in stone.
  * **Join a Forum:**  HiFi Public forums  are a great place to talk about technology, science, and culture. In order to post in a forum, you need to “join” it. To do that, just visit the forum you’d like to join and click the “join” button in the upper right. When you do, your membership to the forum will appear on your user profile.
  * **Get in touch:**  Have a news tip? Want to contact the moderators? See a bug? You can do all of that right here.

###  RULES OF THE ROAD

Here are things that will get your comment or forum posts removed and quite possibly get you banned. Note that this is not a comprehensive list. Our moderators reserve the right to remove anything we deem inappropriate.

  * **Spam:**  Zero tolerance, of course! If it comes from a human or a robot, spam will be deleted. This includes self-promotion. Generally speaking, promoting your projects here will be treated like any other spam.
  * **Personal attacks:**  Don’t attack or insult another user. It’s not helpful and it doesn’t make  _Bluescheme_  a friendly place. This includes calling other members trolls.
  * **Illegal activities:**  Posting links to illegal downloads; ways to steal service, and other nefarious activity is not OK here.
  * **NSFW material:**  Nope, not allowed. Even images or links that could be considered borderline are not acceptable. A good rule of thumb is that anything beyond PG-13 will get you in trouble, but we reserve the right to remove any post we deem offensive. This goes for porngraphic material, vile language, gore and generally gross stuff.
  * **Racism, sexism, and other discrimination:**  Attacking entire classes of people are just like attacking a single person: we’ll ban you for it.
  * **Trolling:**  ”Trolling” is a big, messy term, but we know what trolls are and we won’t tolerate it. If you’re abusing the good conversations here at _  HiFi Public_, we will take your comments and posts down. This includes taking a thread off-topic, by the way.
  * **Multiple accounts and throwaway emails:**  We don’t allow multiple accounts per user. Using a disposable email address signals to us that you might not be here for the right reasons. You also may not create accounts designed to impersonate another person.
  * **Cross posting:**  Don’t make duplicate posts across different forums — it clogs things up and fractures the conversation.
  * **Complaining about coverage:**  We cover a wide array of topics, not all of which are easy, comfortable, or reflective of your personal views. This applies doubly to review scores. While we’re not against discussions of our coverage, plainly stated accusations of bias are usually an indication that you’re not trying to be a productive member of the community.

Above all, our team of moderators works to keep conversation here friendly, engaging, helpful, and productive. If we feel a comment or forum post is harming that endeavor, we’ll take action.

See any of the above? You can help us out by flagging (more on that below). Any comments that are a reply to spammy/inappropriate/trolling comments will also be deleted with the original comment, so don’t reply — just flag!

### MODERATION

  * **Isn’t this censorship?**  Well, no and yes. We’re trying to foster great conversation and we will remove comments that harm that endeavor. You’re free to say whatever you like other places, but not here. At  _HiFi Public_  we have a different standard, working very hard to keep the conversation informative and fun. The bottom line is that the editors and moderators have the final say on whether it fits within our community guidelines.
  * **Questions about moderation:**  We’re happy to have a discussion with you about it —  _in private_. We’ve found from long and hard experience that public complaints about moderation just leads to people trying to “game” the system. If you have a question about moderation, hit us up on our contact form and we’ll have a talk. If there’s a big policy change or something we would like to say publicly about moderation, we’ll post it in our Meta forums and update this document.
  * **Helping out our moderators:**  Moderators work very, very hard with your best interests at heart. Please help them out by flagging inappropriate comments and take heed when they ask you to change your behavior. Note that most of our moderators are volunteers freely dedicating their time to help make things better. They don’t speak for the site, but still deserve your gratitude.
  * **Becoming a mod:**  We don’t have an application process, we select from the best members of our community. If you want to be a mod, our advice to you is to be awesome: help users when they have questions, flag inappropriate comments with good explanations of why, help users relax when threads start to look like flamewars, and generally just show us that you’re a helpful and real human being. When the time comes, we may tap you on the shoulder and ask if you’re interested.

### COMMENTS

Comments are a lovely way to talk about the stories, forum posts, and reviews you find on  _HiFi Public_. They can also be a lot to keep up with, so we have some tools to make it all easier. You can preview your comment before you post it, and you will have 90 seconds to edit a comment afterwards. Every comment also has a few links associated with it:

  * **Reply:**  Use this to reply to that specific comment. Your reply will be threaded to that comment.
  * **Recommend:**  We love great comments and we know you do too. Click the “Recommend” link to vote up a comment and see it get more love and affection from the site.
  * **Flag:**  This is the link you use to report a post to the moderators. Use it on spam, on personal attacks, or on racist or sexist language. Do not use it to report stuff you disagree with or to hassle users. Our moderators and operators really work hard so please co-operate as much as possible.

It’s important to know that comments are threaded and if the top comment in a thread is a problem, we may delete it, and that will delete all the replies to it. So if there’s an inappropriate comment and you reply to it with something eloquent and heartfelt, there’s a very good chance that your highly intelligent and meaningful comment will nonetheless be lost.

### FORUM POSTS

_HiFi Public_  offers a full WYSIWYG (What You See Is What You Get) editor on forum posts.

Our editors and moderators will be watching out for great content to promote on the site as well as inappropriate content. In other words, all the rules above about spam, abusive behavior, and basic human decency apply double to forum posts. You can help!  **Recommend**  or  **Flag**  forum posts to bring them to our attention. If a forum post is terrible, please flag it instead of commenting — even if the comments are great, we will remove forum posts that run against our community guidelines.

Finally, please post in the appropriate forum. Have a question about the new iPhone? Apple Core is the place. If we again portray us,  _HiFi Public_  itself, we have a Meta forum.  If you want help to compare an Android phone to a BlackBerry? We have a general Mobile forum for that. Not sure where your post belongs? Ask in Meta or ask us directly.

### COMMENTS VS. FORUM POSTS

Although there is no hard and fast rule for when you should make a comment on somebody else’s post or when you should make a new forum post, we do have some clear guidelines. Essentially, if there is already a post on a topic you’re interested in talking about, it’s better to comment on that post than to make a new one. We have a very large search box at the top of the forums and we encourage all users to search before you post. Duplicate posts may be closed or removed.

### ACCOUNT ALTERATIONS

Need to disable your account, request a name change? Just get in touch with the moderators and operators and they can help you out.

### ETHICS STATEMENT

We take ethics and transparency very seriously here at  _HiFi Public_ , and we strive to provide you with coverage that is fair, accurate, and transparent. We refuse to be involved in any negative provocation for political, economic or social matters. To accomplish that, we operate our site based on the principles we’ve shared with you.

We also welcome questions, comments, and concerns about our coverage, and we invite you to contact us with any issues and feedback you might have.

Your privacy is important to us and we have prepared this Privacy Policy to explain to you how we collect, use, and share information we obtain through your use of the Internet sites, applications and services (“Services”) that are operated by, controlled by or are affiliate with BlueScheme Ltd., including without limitation HiFiPublic.com. This Privacy Policy does not govern our use of any information you provide to us when you call us, write to us, or communicate with us in any manner other than through the Services. Because the Internet is global, information about you that we collect or that you submit may be transferred to, processed in, and held in countries (including Bangladesh) other than the one in which you reside.

**By using the Services, you explicitly consent to such use of your information and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.**

  1. **1.      ****Information We Automatically Collect.**

We automatically collect certain information to help us understand how our users use the Services (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as  **“Usage Data”** ). For example, each time you visit the Services we may automatically collect your IP address, browser and computer type, access time, the Web page you came from, the URL you go to next, and the Web page(s) that you access during your visit.

We will use such Usage Data to diagnose problems with our servers and software, to administer the Services, and to gather demographic information. Our third-party advertising networks and servers will also provide us reports that will tell us how many ads were presented and clicked on the Services in a manner that does not identify personally any individual.

  1. **2.      ****Information You Choose To Submit.**

You can visit the Services without telling us who you are or revealing any information by which someone could personally identify you (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as  **“Personal Information”** ). If, however, you wish to register to become a member of the Services, you are required to provide certain Personal Information (e.g., your name and e-mail address), and we ask that you also provide a user name and password. We use your Personal Information to fulfill your requests for products and services, to improve our Services, and to contact you from time to time about us, and our products and services. You may also choose to submit additional information about yourself (for example your gender, birth date, or zip code) by which someone could not personally identify you (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as  **“Non-Personal Information”** ). We may also collect additional information about you when you visit certain features of the Services or the pages of certain of our partners when you interact with offers and advertisements, when you contact us for support, when you log into the Services with your account, when you complete a survey, or when you enter promotions. Finally, you may choose to submit your alias, bio, email, photos or any other information that you would like to share with other users of the Services (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as  **“Shared Information”** ).

  1. **3.      ****Our Information Sharing Practices**

**(a) Generally** **,** we may share your Usage Data, Personal Information, Non-Personal Information, or Shared Information (which we will refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as “User Information”) with any third party without your permission.

**(b) Advertisers.**  From time to time, we may share your Usage Data and Non-Personal Information to enable third parties who serve advertisements on the Services to deliver advertisements that will be relevant to you. We will not share any such information, however, in a manner that would enable the advertiser to personally identify you.

**(c) Aggregated Data.**  From time to time, we may share aggregated User Information with third parties. We will not share any aggregated data, however, in manner that would enable the recipient to personally identify you.

**(d) Service Providers.**  From time to time, we may enter into relationships with third parties who provide services to us (e.g., data management and storage services or credit card processing services). In those circumstances, we disclose User Information that is necessary for such service providers to perform those services and require that they maintain the confidentiality of such User Information.

**(e) Other Disclosure Scenarios.**  Notwithstanding anything in this Privacy Policy to the contrary, we reserve the right, and you hereby expressly authorize us, to share any User Information: (1) in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims; (2) if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, fraud, or situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or property; (3) if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding significant abuse of the Services’ infrastructure or the Internet in general (such as voluminous spamming, denial of service attacks, or attempts to compromise the security of information); (4) to our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us (in which case we will require such entities to honor this Privacy Policy); and (5) if we are acquired by or merged with another entity.

  1. **4.      ****Public Information.**

If you identify any User Information as public, you are authorizing us to share such information publicly. For example, you may elect to make certain Shared Information (such as your alias, bio, email or photos) publicly available. Also, there may be areas of the Services (e.g., message boards, discussion rooms, and other online forums) in which you are able to post information that will be available to all other users of the Services. By choosing to use these areas, you understand and agree that anyone may access, use, and disclose any information that you post to those areas.

  1. **5.      ****Cookies.**

We may set and access cookies on your computer. Upon your first visit to the Services, a cookie is sent to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. A “cookie” is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer and stored on your hard drive when you visit a website. Many major Web services use cookies to provide useful features for their users. Each web site can send its own cookie to your browser. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent; however if you reject cookies, you will not be able to sign in to the Services or take full advantage of our Services.

We use cookies for the following general purposes: (a) to track your preferences, such as the address or local zip code you enter; (b) to access your information when you sign in so we can provide you with your personalized content; (c) to display the most appropriate advertisements, based on your interests and activity on our Services; and (d) to help us improve the Services by analyzing and estimating our traffic and use of features on the Services.

We may also use “pixel tags,” which are small graphic files that allow us to monitor the use of the Services. A pixel tag can collect information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the tag appears; the URL of the page on which the pixel tag appears; the time (and length of time) the page containing the pixel tag was viewed; the type of browser that retrieved the pixel tag; and the identification number of any cookie previously placed by that server on your computer.

We may use pixel tags, either provided by us or by our third party advertisers and ad networks, to collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click and other actions taken in connection with our sites and Services and use them in combination with our cookies to provide offers and information of interest to you.

We also may allow certain analytic services and providers of applications used on the Services (e.g., sharing buttons) to collect Non-Personally Identifiable information by placing cookies on the Services that will track certain performance of our Services, such as, web traffic, click-through, etc., in order to assist us and our service providers in better understanding the interests of our users and to better serve those interests.

  1. **6.      ****Advertising.**

We may use other companies under agreements with us to serve advertisements when you visit and use the Services. These companies may collect and use click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over during your visits to the Services and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie, a third party web beacon and/or pixel tags to collect this information. None of them collect any personal information from your computer, such as your e-mail address. Other companies’ use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Advertisers or other companies do not have access to our cookies.

  1. **7.      ****Targeted Advertising.**

In order to serve offers and advertisements that may be interest to our users, we may display targeted advertisements on the Services based on Personal Information provided by our users, including zip code and profile. We do not provide this Personal Information to our advertisers when you interact with such an advertisement. However, please note that the advertisers (including ad serving companies) may determine based on their own analysis that a user who interacts with an advertisement targeted by us may fit into a certain demographic category; for example, an advertiser may determine that men ages 25-34 are interacting with a certain advertisement on the Services from a particular geographic area.

  1. **8.      ****Your Options and Information about Advertisers and Targeted Ads.**

You can learn more about the advertising companies we work with and what options they may offer you regarding cookies and targeted advertising by contacting us. Many of these companies are also members of the Network Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance, which each provide a simple way to opt-out of ad targeting from participating companies.

  1. **9.      ****Mobile.**

We may from time to time offer certain location or pinpoint based services with our applications (such as, GPS assisted navigation instruction, wireless tower location, triangulation or other available location technologies). If you elect to use such location based services, we must periodically receive your location in order to provide such location-based services to you. By using the applications’ location based services, you authorize us to: (a) locate your hardware; (b) record, compile and display your location; and (c) publish your location to third parties designated by you by means of location publication controls available within the applications (e.g., settings, user preferences). As part of the applications, we may also collect and store certain information about our users, such as, users’ wireless mobile subscriber ISDN and/or IMEI numbers (as applicable) and users’ network access identifier information. This information will be used to provide you the services accessed through our applications. We may use third party providers to help provide services through mobile systems and such providers may use the information in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

**10.** **Choice/Opt-Out.**

We offer you the opportunity to choose not to receive communications from us. If you would like to take advantage of this opportunity, please let us know by accessing and updating your profile. Please note that sometimes these requests may take up to ten business days to process and that we are not responsible for removing information about you from the database of any third party to whom we were authorized to disclose your User Information prior to processing your request. Even if you do take advantage of this opportunity, we reserve the right to send you administrative messages relating to the Services (e.g., about changes to this Privacy Policy) and to contact you regarding any goods or services you have ordered.

**11.** **Modifying and Deleting Your Personal Information.**

If you would like to modify or delete from our database any User Information you previously submitted to us, please let us know by accessing and updating your profile. Please note that any User Information that we have copied may remain in back-up storage for some period of time after your request, and that if you delete certain information you may not be able to order services in the future without re-submitting such information. Also, please note that we will maintain User Information in our database whenever we are required to do so by law.

**12.** **Security.**

We have implemented reasonable measures to help protect your User Information from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access or disclosure. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your User Information, we cannot guarantee its security.

**13.** **Links.**

The Services may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any such other website and urge you to review such practices prior to submitting any information to such websites.

**14.** **Children’s Privacy.**

We are committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. The Services are not intended for and may not be used by children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and we do not target the Services to children under the age of 13.

**15.** **Changes.**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If under any such update we make any material change to the way in which we treat your User Information, we will inform you of such change via email or by posting a notice on relevant areas of the Services. Any updated version of this Privacy Policy will be effective as of the date set forth therein.

**16.** **Questions.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us by email at: info@hifipublic.com
